Jurriaan Engels

Jurriaanengels@hotmail.nl

Amsterdam

Website

LinkedIn

Analytically minded entry-level data scientist/data analyst with a passion for data visualisation, data knowledge and statistics. I am excited to share my insights and experience to a team of likeminded indivduals where questions lead to new discoveries and high-quality data analytics.

WORK EXPERIENCE

A.S.R. - Junior Consultant (Data Science Traineeship via House of Bèta) December 2022 – Present

- Handle customer and business partner complaints, provide appropriate solutions and alternatives within the time limits. Communicating with other departments if necessary.
- Build sustainable relationships and trust with customer accounts through open and interactive communication while following communication procedures, guidelines and policies.
- Providing both specific content-related and general information about products, policies and services
 of life insurances at A.S.R.

TNO - Graduate Intern September 2021 – May 2022

- Researched privacy enhancing techniques and how to combine these with graph neural networks in order to generate privacy preserving graphical transaction data.
- Providing entry-level knowledge of this subject to the data science department through presentations and setting them up for a bigger related project.
- Worked with several data scientists at TNO and two data scientists from two different financial institutions in order to define the quality metrics of the model.

EDUCATION

University of Amsterdam - Master's, Mathematics (Specialization: Stochastics and Statistics) September 2019 – May 2022 **University of Amsterdam** - Bachelor's, Mathematics
September 2016 – July 2019

SKILLS

Python (NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Keras, Tensorflow), R, Apache Spark, Azure Databricks, Git, Excel, VBA, SQL, PowerBI, Tableau, LaTeX, HTML, CSS.

COURSES/TRAININGS

Statistical Data Analysis (UvA), Advanced Machine Learning (MasterMath), Dynamic Programming and Reinforcement Learning (MasterMath), Kickstart Excel, VBA, Python (HoB)

CERTIFICATES

Agile Scrum Foundation – Basic fundamentals of agile and scrum project planning techniques and how to apply them in practice.

Machine Learning: A to Z (Udemy, ongoing) - Course on data preprocessing, regression, classification, clustering, RL, NLP, deep learning, dimensionality reduction and model selection in Python and R. IBM Data Science (Coursera, ongoing) - Course on importing and cleaning datasets, analyze and visualize data, and build and evaluate machine learning models in Python and R.